<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scrum Agile Board on Oliver Wehrens</title>
    <link>https://owehrens.com/categories/scrum-agile-board/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scrum Agile Board on Oliver Wehrens</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://owehrens.com/categories/scrum-agile-board/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Updated Scrum Board Cheat Sheet with Story Owner</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/updated-scrum-board-cheat-sheet-with-story-owner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/updated-scrum-board-cheat-sheet-with-story-owner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So just in the last sprint we (re) discovered that we need an&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; owner of each story&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. A person who makes sure things are going smoothly and takes care that everything is done in a way so we can fulfill all acceptance tests. At sprint start the person which feels the strongest about the first story will be owner and he will drive the story.&#xA;Very often we do operate in a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;king and servant&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; model. The king (story owner) calls as many servants he needs to get &amp;lsquo;his&amp;rsquo; story (with the highest priority) done. If this story does not scale to the full team the others are starting on the next story. Again, a story owner (king) is chosen (or whoever wants to drive the story). Of course story priority is always determining the order of allocating resources to finish the job.&#xA;To formalize the story owner a little bit we do write down the name of the person in the upper right corner of the story card. I updated the scrum board cheat sheet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
