<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monolith on Oliver Wehrens</title>
    <link>https://owehrens.com/tags/monolith/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monolith on Oliver Wehrens</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://owehrens.com/tags/monolith/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Entwicklung verteilter Systeme - Herausforderungen nicht nur an die Architektur</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/entwicklung-verteilter-systeme-herausforderungen-nicht-nur-an-die-architektur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/entwicklung-verteilter-systeme-herausforderungen-nicht-nur-an-die-architektur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my talk about &lt;strong&gt;Development of distributed systems - challenges not only for the architecture&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; You guessed it, it is in german. I gave this talk at &lt;a href=&#34;http://bed-con.org/2015/talks/Entwicklung-verteilter-Systeme---Herausforderungen-nicht-nur-an-die-Architektur&#34;&gt;BedCon 2015&lt;/a&gt; and I will talk about it again at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.the-architecture-gathering.de/indexEN.php&#34;&gt;Architecture Gathering 2015&lt;/a&gt; in Munich on October 22nd.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;script async class=&#34;speakerdeck-embed&#34; data-id=&#34;af49bc1ea74b4fefaeaa3636c69542cd&#34; data-ratio=&#34;1.33333333333333&#34; src=&#34;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jede Platform wächst mit der Zeit. Mehr Entwickler mit noch mehr Ideen und Vorstellungen arbeiten alle gemeinsam an der Weiterentwicklung. Das System wird größer und auf viele Systeme verteilt. Häufig wird ein Technologie Stack vorgegeben, um es vermeintlich wartbarer und stabiler zu machen. Zusätzlich wird die Software oft dabei von Entwicklung zu QA weitergereicht und am Schluss von Operations deployed und betrieben. Das Ergebnis davon sind lange Releasezyklen und das verschenkte Potenzial, weil nicht die richtigen Tools genutzt werden konnten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating a monolith</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/migrating-a-monolith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/migrating-a-monolith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you start, a monolith is much easier to begin with. Everything is in one place, it&amp;rsquo;s fast and all team members understand the code.&#xA;If you plan your application from the start as distributed system in a microservice like style, you add some significant overhead. Don&amp;rsquo;t do it, &lt;a href=&#34;https://owehrens.com/a-monolith-could-be-good-for-you/&#34;&gt;monoliths have their advantages&lt;/a&gt; at some point. If another team start with the same project or more functionality is added, splitting up the monolith might be a way to go. Looking at ways to migrate, you maybe can do some better  design decision to for you monolith.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you don&#39;t fight it you end up with a monolith</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/if-you-dont-fight-it-you-end-up-with-a-monolith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/if-you-dont-fight-it-you-end-up-with-a-monolith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You planned your software. You talked to your business owners. As soon as you saw a new use case which should be implemented, you modularized it. You did everything right. And then you hit the integration layer. Sounds familiar?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At some point in your project you need to integrate all modules with each other. In case of a website you need to produce HTML.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are different approaches how to tackle this problem. You can integrate it on the server side, grabbing all ui code from the affected systems and pack it together or you can integrate it in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Monolith could be good for you</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/a-monolith-could-be-good-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/a-monolith-could-be-good-for-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everybody says monolithic applications are bad. I usually hear things like:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tiny changes need full redeployment (maybe even with downtime)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Limited agility&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Easy to get a big ball of mud&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So why would you like to have a monolith?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://owehrens.com/static/monoliths.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Monolith&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many definitions of a monolithic application. There are tons  for microservices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Monolith has it&amp;rsquo;s advantages. There are companies which are successful with monolithic applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;you-start-faster&#34;&gt;You start faster.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s one codebase. All in one editor. Only one team working on it. Why would you split that into multiple projects, thinking about interfaces and deployment? If you start with a new project I would recommend to do it just like that. Dealing with multiple services right from the start adds overhead and complexity which you can avoid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How you might know that you have a monolith</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/how-you-might-know-that-you-have-a-monolith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/how-you-might-know-that-you-have-a-monolith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You start your green field project and keep working on it. It grows and grows and grows. You feel comfortable with it and it could not be better. Because more needs to be done/the product is successful another team is added.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://owehrens.com/static/monolith150150.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Monolith&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If this &lt;strong&gt;new team starts&lt;/strong&gt; complaining that the setup if very complicated and they do take a lot of time to get started:&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Listen carefully&lt;/strong&gt;. Of course everybody will complain if they get thrown into another code base, nobody understands the code and of course everybody would have it done differently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
