<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Oliver Wehrens</title>
    <link>https://example.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Oliver Wehrens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clean code ... should you DRY?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/clean-code-should-you-dry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/clean-code-should-you-dry/</guid>
      <description>2008 Robert C. Martin published his book &amp;lsquo;Clean Code&amp;rsquo;. I was just starting my new job as Senior Software Developer at Hypoport. It was eye-opening. We discussed it in a tech department wide book circle, exchanged ideas of what things mean and agreed to some standards which are important to us.&#xA;Over the years, I learned that people took that as the bible. And it went further. My favourite example of taking it religiously is: Don&amp;rsquo;t repeat yourself (DRY).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why you need a macro architecture</title>
      <link>https://example.org/why-you-need-a-macro-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/why-you-need-a-macro-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Eberhard Wolff on LinkedIn asked recently: &amp;lsquo;What was the biggest mistake you witnessed or did?&amp;rsquo; (in software architecture).&#xA;The one thing which came to my mind is that at one point we did not have a shared understanding how we should build our system back when I was working at DHL E-POST. This was in ~ 2014. We split the monolith in multiple services. Every team (we had 10 teams) was doing it how they thought it would be good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can AI replace me as a consultant?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/can-ai-replace-me-as-a-consultant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/can-ai-replace-me-as-a-consultant/</guid>
      <description>I got recently asked if my job as a consultant in the tech, product and organizations development space, can be replaced by an AI.&#xA;I said, that I&amp;rsquo;m that arrogant to think that this is not possible.&#xA;After thinking about it for a few days I was wondering: Is that so?&#xA;Usually our customers call us to get help or for an outside view on their (digital) product development. This includes observing everything around product, technology &amp;amp; organization, help implementing improvements and enable the customer to be more effective and efficient after we leave.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whisper: Nvidia RTX 4090 vs M1Pro with MLX (updated with M2/M3)</title>
      <link>https://example.org/whisper-nvidia-rtx-4090-vs-m1pro-with-mlx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/whisper-nvidia-rtx-4090-vs-m1pro-with-mlx/</guid>
      <description>(&amp;hellip; see down below for M2 Ultra / M3 Max Update and a Nvidia optimzied whisper)&#xA;Apple released a machine learning framework for Apple Silicon. Along with that are some examples to see how things are working. They also use a whisper for benchmarking. So I dug out my benchmark and used that to measure performance.&#xA;I simply added a new file to the repo (and the whisper large model was already downloaded).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artifacts for effective alignment</title>
      <link>https://example.org/artifacts-for-effective-alignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/artifacts-for-effective-alignment/</guid>
      <description>In my professional life, I came across many different companies and organizations. The majority of those were digital companies with its own Tech and Product departments (and only there might the following text applicable). If you have not found your product/market fit, it might be a different game. But if you have, read on.&#xA;One of the biggest complications was always the alignment of where to go and how to get there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcast time</title>
      <link>https://example.org/podcast-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/podcast-time/</guid>
      <description>No, I did not start my own. Ivan of dev.env podcast invited me to talk about how I got there, where I am. Thanks for having me Ivan. It was fun.&#xA;Sorry, German only.&#xA;https://shows.acast.com/dev-env/episodes/18-oliver-wehrens</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Whisper Performance on Nvidia RTX 4090</title>
      <link>https://example.org/whisper-performance-on-nvidia-rtx-4090/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/whisper-performance-on-nvidia-rtx-4090/</guid>
      <description>Short update on my performance series on OpenAI Whisper running on T4 / A100 and Apple Silicon.&#xA;I got my hands on a Nvidia RTX 4090 and ran a 3600 seconds audio file through it.&#xA;GPU 0 NVIDIA GeForce RTX 4090 Load Model at 2023-03-21 17:22:09.623805 Loading took 0:00:09.574030 started at 2023-03-21 17:22:19.197835 ended at 2023-03-21 17:25:25.905605 time elapsed: 0:03:06.707770 With the large model it makes a ~ 19.3 x speed up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Search with Cosine Similarity</title>
      <link>https://example.org/semantic-search-with-cosine-similarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/semantic-search-with-cosine-similarity/</guid>
      <description>If you have a lot of text, how do you search though it? Keywords? What if these keywords never show up there? Imagine you want to know if Jerome Powell says something about &amp;lsquo;Inflation decrease&amp;rsquo; but he might not say the exact words? You will not find it. Databases like Meilisearch offer synonyms, but this can only take you so far.&#xA;Similarity Enter semantic search.&#xA;I first heard about it when I saw that OpenAI offers this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Whisper Benchmark Nvidia Tesla T4 / A100</title>
      <link>https://example.org/openai-whisper-benchmark-on-nvidia-tesla-t4-a100/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/openai-whisper-benchmark-on-nvidia-tesla-t4-a100/</guid>
      <description>In my previous article, I wondered how OpenAI Whisper C++ Edition on a MacBook Pro M1Pro stacks up against a CUDA card. I don&amp;rsquo;t have one, so I could not do the test.&#xA;Benchmarking Nvidia Tesla T4 Google Colab to the rescue. I totally forgot about it. I can run (for free) on an Nvidia T4. If you start a notebook for yourself, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to set the Runtime to GPU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Whisper on Apple M1</title>
      <link>https://example.org/openai-whisper-on-apple-m1-cpp-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/openai-whisper-on-apple-m1-cpp-version/</guid>
      <description>OpenAI released Whisper in September 2022 as Open Source. To achieve good performance, you need an Nvidia CUDA GPU with &amp;gt; 8 GB VRAM.&#xA;Recently, Georgi Gerganov released a C++ port optimized for CPU and especially Apple Silicon Platform. So I tried this out.&#xA;I run all of that on a Macbook Pro with a M1Pro CPU (6 performance and 2 efficiency cores) and 32 GB RAM. I want to run one 10 minute audio file in German with different number of cores and different models (tiny, base, small, medium, large).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does it take to become a software architect?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/what-does-it-take-to-become-a-software-architekt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/what-does-it-take-to-become-a-software-architekt/</guid>
      <description>I got together with Eberhard Wolff to discuss and answer questions about what it takes to become a Software Architekt on Software Architektur TV. He was asked by several people what kind of skills a software architect needs, how a recruitment process might look or what kind of advice he could give to students to become an architect. So we got together and talked about it with live questions from the audience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How hands-on should a CTO be?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/how-hands-on-should-a-cto-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/how-hands-on-should-a-cto-be/</guid>
      <description>I got asked on LinkedIn, so here is my answer.&#xA;It depends (on the phase of the company).&#xA;I like Simon Wardley&amp;rsquo;s Mapping. He defines categories of company phases&#xA;Pioneers (searching for Product-Market Fit) Settlers (might have found Product-Market Fit) Town planners (Found something to grow) A job in an early startup is very different from a big corporation. I also assume that while going through the phases, the company grows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sketch Book Summary: No Estimates</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sketch-book-summary-no-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sketch-book-summary-no-estimates/</guid>
      <description>Here is my Sketch Book Summary of No Estimates by Vasco Duarte.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four weeks of home office</title>
      <link>https://example.org/four-weeks-of-home-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/four-weeks-of-home-office/</guid>
      <description>On March 12th we decided to send everybody into Home office. We were partially already working remotely but we never tried to be 100%. Now we were forced to.&#xA;As a summary: It works better than I expected. The remote work is not as much as a problem for everybody. Being stuck at home is.&#xA;Tools (don’t fix problems) We already had bits and pieces in place to enable remote collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sketch Book Summary: Good Strategy, Bad Strategy</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sketch-book-summary-good-strategy-bad-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sketch-book-summary-good-strategy-bad-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Here is my Sketch Book Summary about Good Stratgey, Bad Strategy. Thanks to Daniel for recommending it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2019</title>
      <link>https://example.org/my-year-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/my-year-2019/</guid>
      <description>Lots of things have changed for me in 2019. So let’s look back.&#xA;In 2019, the biggest project I was ever involved in and responsible for went live. Nothing happened at launch day and everything started to work smoothly. We worked the whole of 2018 with up to 10 teams on this project. That was a very cool experience. Thanks to everybody who was involved. It would not have been possible without all of you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Agility</title>
      <link>https://example.org/technical-agility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/technical-agility/</guid>
      <description>I was giving a talk at an internal event of a consulting firm on Technical Agility. Here are my experiences and ideas on that topic.&#xA;I will touch on&#xA;What Why Where How ( &amp;amp; How to measure) I will only touch on technical aspects of this topic. There is so much more to it like organization, team structure, culture and trust.&#xA;The ability to react to changes is the reason I want to have Technical Agility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wardley Mapping Canvas</title>
      <link>https://example.org/wardley-mapping-canvas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/wardley-mapping-canvas/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Simon Wardley&amp;rsquo;s Maps.&#xA;Ben Mosior over at Miro came up with a nice canvas for Wardley mapping. I could not find a vector version for printing out, so I made one with Affinity Designer.&#xA;They are available at my Github Repository. It contains the original .afdesign file as well as a PDF version with and without explanation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Sketch Book Summary (SBS) to remember content what matters to me.</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sketch-book-summary-sbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sketch-book-summary-sbs/</guid>
      <description>Over the time I developed my own way of remembering what the content of a book was. I&amp;rsquo;m reading a lot self improvement, time management, management and culture books. A trainer once told me if I could remember months later only 10% what was in the book I&amp;rsquo;m really good. I wanted to change that.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m reading mostly on my Kindle. I have all the books always with me. The nice thing about it is, that I could mark text which is important or useful to me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sketch Book Summary: Atomic Habits</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sbs-atomic-habbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sbs-atomic-habbits/</guid>
      <description>Below my summary about the Book Atomic Habits by James Clear. This is how I try remember some ideas in books. There is another post about this and why I do it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CD und DevOps im Expertencheck</title>
      <link>https://example.org/cd-und-devops-im-expertencheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/cd-und-devops-im-expertencheck/</guid>
      <description>Grau ist alle Theorie. Wir haben daher verschiedene Experten zum Thema Continuous Delivery und DevOps befragt – wir wollten wissen, wie ihre Erfahrungen mit den eigenen Teams und Unternehmen verlaufen sind. Oft stellte sich heraus, dass die Technik an sich nicht das größte Problem ist.&#39;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warum wir auf DevOps setzen</title>
      <link>https://example.org/warum-wir-auf-devops-setzen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/warum-wir-auf-devops-setzen/</guid>
      <description>Die Konkurrenz ist groß, jeder will beim Ausliefern der Software der schnellste sein. Warum wir dabei auf DevOps setzen? Das sind die Argumente.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2017-90 - Random Tech Links</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2017-90-random-tech-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/2017-90-random-tech-links/</guid>
      <description>Automating Kubernetes Cluster Operations with OperatorsThe goal is to give end-users a carefree Kubernetes-as-a-Service (KaaS) no matter the underlying infrastructure. Most importantly that means getting the full vanilla Kubernetes experience out-of-the-box. A fully functional local AWS cloud stack. Develop and test your cloud apps offline!LocalStack provides an easy-to-use test/mocking framework for developing Cloud applications. Currently, the focus is primarily on supporting the AWS cloud stack. LocalStack spins up the following core Cloud APIs on your local machine: API Gateway, Kinesis, DynamoDB, DynamoDB Streams, Elasticsearch, S3, Firehose, Lambda, SNS, SQS, Redshift Automating Your Security Acceptance TestsAutomate security tests with the open source OWASP ZAP proxy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Service Discovery For Machines And Humans</title>
      <link>https://example.org/service-discovery-for-machines-and-humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 20:54:58 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/service-discovery-for-machines-and-humans/</guid>
      <description>My slides from the OOP 2017 conference.&#xA;Abstract: Combining Continuous Deployment and a Microservice architecture brings new challenges to develop and operate your platform. A service discovery enables you to build a flexible system. Developers need to have an up to date view on the deployed services as well. A human readable registry with relevant information is needed. I will outline what we solved with a Service Registry and what impact it had on our architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microservices bei der E-POST</title>
      <link>https://example.org/microservices-bei-der-e-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/microservices-bei-der-e-post/</guid>
      <description>Microservices sind in aller Munde, und auf Konferenzen versprechen Migrationsszenarien und technische Details gut besuchte Vorträge. Eine Folie, die fast immer auftaucht, ist eine Feststellung von Melvin Conway aus dem Jahr 1968, die besagt, dass „Organisationen, die Systeme entwerfen, […] auf Entwürfe festgelegt sind, welche die Kommunikationsstrukturen dieser Organisationen abbilden.“ (Conways Law). Das heißt konkret, dass sich die Organisation der Firma und der Teams ­direkt auf den Code und die Architektur auswirkt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Der Real-Life-Check</title>
      <link>https://example.org/der-real-life-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/der-real-life-check/</guid>
      <description>Über Microservices wird momentan viel in Theorie geschrieben und gesprochen. Doch wie sieht es in der wahren Welt dort draußen aus? Wir haben die Autoren dieses Themenschwerpunkts und weitere Experten aus der Branche gefragt, wie ihre Microservices-Erfahrungen aus der Praxis sind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How is your microservice architecture doing?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/how-is-your-microservice-architecture-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/how-is-your-microservice-architecture-doing/</guid>
      <description>It all started when my new boss stepped into my door and asked me if I had a clue how our system was working. In an ideal world we would have teams and developers who work on a isolated context with clear boundaries. They develop, test, deploy, monitor and operate everything by themselves. They are on 24/7 call and therefore they do everything possible that nothing fails. The system is stable and brings in the money.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entwicklung verteilter Systeme - Herausforderungen nicht nur an die Architektur</title>
      <link>https://example.org/entwicklung-verteilter-systeme-herausforderungen-nicht-nur-an-die-architektur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/entwicklung-verteilter-systeme-herausforderungen-nicht-nur-an-die-architektur/</guid>
      <description>This is my talk about Development of distributed systems - challenges not only for the architecture. You guessed it, it is in german. I gave this talk at BedCon 2015 and I will talk about it again at the Architecture Gathering 2015 in Munich on October 22nd. Abstract:&#xA;Jede Platform wächst mit der Zeit. Mehr Entwickler mit noch mehr Ideen und Vorstellungen arbeiten alle gemeinsam an der Weiterentwicklung. Das System wird größer und auf viele Systeme verteilt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wider den Monolith - Am Ende wird alles gut</title>
      <link>https://example.org/wider-den-monolith-am-ende-wird-alles-gut/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/wider-den-monolith-am-ende-wird-alles-gut/</guid>
      <description> My WJax 2014 talk in german. Wider den Monolith - Am Ende wird alles gut. My first talk with lots of pictures. The talk was recorded. As soon as I know the url I will post it here (and if I&#39;m not too embarrassed :) ). Update: Here is the video (in german). </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating a monolith</title>
      <link>https://example.org/migrating-a-monolith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/migrating-a-monolith/</guid>
      <description>If you start, a monolith is much easier to begin with. Everything is in one place, it&amp;rsquo;s fast and all team members understand the code. If you plan your application from the start as distributed system in a microservice like style, you add some significant overhead. Don&amp;rsquo;t do it, monoliths have their advantages at some point. If another team start with the same project or more functionality is added, splitting up the monolith might be a way to go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you don&#39;t fight it you end up with a monolith</title>
      <link>https://example.org/if-you-dont-fight-it-you-end-up-with-a-monolith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/if-you-dont-fight-it-you-end-up-with-a-monolith/</guid>
      <description>You planned your software. You talked to your business owners. As soon as you saw a new use case which should be implemented, you modularized it. You did everything right. And then you hit the integration layer. Sounds familiar?&#xA;At some point in your project you need to integrate all modules with each other. In case of a website you need to produce HTML.&#xA;There are different approaches how to tackle this problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Monolith could be good for you</title>
      <link>https://example.org/a-monolith-could-be-good-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/a-monolith-could-be-good-for-you/</guid>
      <description>Everybody says monolithic applications are bad. I usually hear things like:&#xA;Tiny changes need full redeployment (maybe even with downtime) Limited agility Easy to get a big ball of mud So why would you like to have a monolith?&#xA;There are many definitions of a monolithic application. There are tons for microservices.&#xA;A Monolith has it&amp;rsquo;s advantages. There are companies which are successful with monolithic applications.&#xA;You start faster. It&amp;rsquo;s one codebase.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How you might know that you have a monolith</title>
      <link>https://example.org/how-you-might-know-that-you-have-a-monolith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/how-you-might-know-that-you-have-a-monolith/</guid>
      <description>You start your green field project and keep working on it. It grows and grows and grows. You feel comfortable with it and it could not be better. Because more needs to be done/the product is successful another team is added.&#xA;If this new team starts complaining that the setup if very complicated and they do take a lot of time to get started: Listen carefully. Of course everybody will complain if they get thrown into another code base, nobody understands the code and of course everybody would have it done differently.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How failing tests can be green</title>
      <link>https://example.org/how-failing-tests-can-be-green/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/how-failing-tests-can-be-green/</guid>
      <description>Imagine this conversation:&#xA;Friend: &amp;ldquo;We have an integration system where we deploy every two weeks all commits and run hundreds of end to end tests on it.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Me: &amp;ldquo;And if everything passed it goes into production?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Friend: &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Me: &amp;ldquo;How often do they fail?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Friend: &amp;ldquo;Uhmm, well like every night. But we just take the failing tests and run them again and after that or the next run they will be green.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Faster</title>
      <link>https://example.org/getting-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/getting-faster/</guid>
      <description> My Continuous Lifecycle 2013 talk. How we got faster at deploying our software. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mit Puppet und RPM</title>
      <link>https://example.org/mit-puppet-und-rpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/mit-puppet-und-rpm/</guid>
      <description>„It works on my machine“ hat sicher jeder schon einmal gehört. In der Entwicklung verhält sich die Software wie erwartet. Bis diese in der Produktion ist, dauert es lange. Einmal live, treten dann unerwartete Fehler auf, während die Softwareentwicklung längst an einer ganz anderen Stelle ist. Wie kann dieser Spagat umgangen werden? Dieser Artikel reflektiert, wie wir mit diesem Problem auf Basis einer paketorientierten Deployment Pipeline umgehen. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing a Sprint Review with a Review Fair</title>
      <link>https://example.org/doing-a-sprint-review-with-a-review-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/doing-a-sprint-review-with-a-review-fair/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working in an organization where we do synchronized sprints between all teams. This means every two weeks all meeting rooms are booked for retrospectives and sprint plannings. If you have around 10-20 teams distributing knowledge what&amp;rsquo;s happening in the other teams is tricky. No one has the time to go to all reviews.&#xA;Enter &amp;lsquo;Review Fair&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;The principle is quite simple. All teams show up in one (big) room. This might be the biggest meeting room you have.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using KVM and Virt-Manager via XQuartz on MacOSX (and solving the keymapping trouble)</title>
      <link>https://example.org/using-kvm-and-virt-manager-via-xquartz-on-macosx-and-solving-the-keymapping-trouble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/using-kvm-and-virt-manager-via-xquartz-on-macosx-and-solving-the-keymapping-trouble/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of months I got to play around with virtualization at work. Doing automated delivery pipleines and provisiong via puppet I decided it&amp;rsquo;s time to get my hands even more dirty at home.&#xA;I got myself a HP Microserver N54L equipped with 16 GB of RAM and 9 TB disks. I wanted ZFS and KVM. Since the machine has an AMD processor the only way was to install Linux on it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with veewee and vagrant</title>
      <link>https://example.org/getting-started-with-veewee-and-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/getting-started-with-veewee-and-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>What do you need to do to get a fully automated kickstart of a virtual machine on your local development platform running? Not much it turns out. There are some tricks to get around but after that it&amp;rsquo;s all fine.&#xA;The resulting image can also be used to get a system in production.&#xA;I will look at the OS installation part. Puppet will come in a later post.&#xA;Installation Tools we will play with:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Development to Production</title>
      <link>https://example.org/from-development-to-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/from-development-to-production/</guid>
      <description> My BedCon 2013 talk. Covering commiting code, packaging,testing, deployment and organisational changes. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do not use Javadoc</title>
      <link>https://example.org/do-not-use-javadoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/do-not-use-javadoc/</guid>
      <description>Javadoc is here to help. To understand what the code does and how it works? Right?&#xA;I don&amp;rsquo;t think so. I confuses the heck out of me in most cases.&#xA;When I look at code like&#xA;/** * Version number of signature. */ public static final String SIGNATURE_VERSION = &amp;#34;1&amp;#34;; I get the feeling that the javadoc is pretty pointless. Well, the damn String is named what it is, how does the Javadoc help me here?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javascript testing for Java projects</title>
      <link>https://example.org/javascript-testing-for-java-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/javascript-testing-for-java-projects/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Java Programmer. I do mostly web projects. There is a tendency to move away from server side frameworks towards Javascript (+mvc) and rest services. This now involves me in programming Javascript at the GUI level. Welcome maven, IDE and continous integration.&#xA;Coming from the JVM world I&amp;rsquo;m pretty much used to writing tests in my IDE running them and then writing the production code. What I found out, this is not that easy with Javascript.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realtime Push Events zum Browser</title>
      <link>https://example.org/realtime-push-events-zum-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/realtime-push-events-zum-browser/</guid>
      <description>WebSockets sind in aller Munde, im Java Magazin sind sie nun sogar Titelthema. Aber es geht auch einfacher: Wer Echtzeit-Events zum Browser schicken will, kann es sich leicht machen. Dieser Artikel zeigt, wie.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber-jvm for Java</title>
      <link>https://example.org/cucumber-jvm-for-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/cucumber-jvm-for-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/concordion-vs-cucumber-and-java-based-acceptance-testing&#34;&gt;earlier&lt;/a&gt; article I compared cucumber (with Cuke4Duke) and Concordion. It was very cumbersome due to the ruby/jruby jvm chain. Behold - the new &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cucumber/cucumber-jvm&#34;&gt;cucumber-jvm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was released. So how did it &lt;strong&gt;improve&lt;/strong&gt; ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cucumber-jvm has support for many languages, e.g. Scala, Groovy, Closure and of course Java. I will focus on &lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Maven&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One assert per test, really</title>
      <link>https://example.org/one-assert-per-test-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/one-assert-per-test-really/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was debugging my code and I could not see why my test was failing. It took me about 20 minutes to see that I violated one rule I try to follow. One assert per test. After tweeting it I got some reaction ranging from &#39;this is a very silly guideline&#39; to &#39;Tests should test one thing. Often one assertion, but not always.&#39;. I, of course, tend to agree the latter one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring 3 MVC, Ajax and jQuery Magic (or better: simplicity)</title>
      <link>https://example.org/spring-3-mvc-ajax-and-jquery-magic-or-better-simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/spring-3-mvc-ajax-and-jquery-magic-or-better-simplicity/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m playing around with some web frameworks lately and to see what&#39;s in store with Spring 3 MVC (never did too much with it) I gave it a try to see how it handles Ajax. According to ajax simplification announcement it should be possible to get up and running in (almost) no time. We will do a simple web application which will show the current time via Ajax. The directory layout (using maven) should look like this: web.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Busy Programmers Guide on where to buy eBooks</title>
      <link>https://example.org/busy-programmers-guide-on-where-to-buy-ebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/busy-programmers-guide-on-where-to-buy-ebooks/</guid>
      <description>Every Programmer needs to read books. Usually you would get some packages from Amazon (or your favorite retailer) and read through them. Now with devices like the Kindle and iPad (and Nook and&amp;hellip;) things will change. No more carrying around a couple of hundred pages of paper. Only some Megabytes on Gigabytes of storage. The displays nowadays are good enough and the battery is not a problem for the most part.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to detect if your server is down when making jQuery Ajax calls </title>
      <link>https://example.org/how-to-detect-if-your-server-is-down-when-making-jquery-ajax-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/how-to-detect-if-your-server-is-down-when-making-jquery-ajax-calls/</guid>
      <description>If you developed an ajax rich web application, maybe even a single page interface, you want to make sure that the user gets notified if the server is not reachable anymore. This happens either if the it goes down or the client loses its network connection. Depending on your code the application can run for a while and the user is confused about missing interactivity.&#xA;So how do you detect this?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Web Prototyping for the Framework loving (Java) Developer</title>
      <link>https://example.org/lightweight-web-prototyping-for-the-framework-loving-java-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/lightweight-web-prototyping-for-the-framework-loving-java-developer/</guid>
      <description>A couple of month ago I had an idea for a small web app. But what does it take to do it ? Do you start with the back end or the front end (read server or client side) ? Typically I would start at the back end, get the domain right and then see how I can fit the UI in. If a programmer starts this way you end with the typical &amp;rsquo;the programmer did the GUI&amp;rsquo; scenario.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How we switched from Subversion to Git</title>
      <link>https://example.org/how-we-switched-from-subversion-to-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/how-we-switched-from-subversion-to-git/</guid>
      <description>So I heard about these strange distributed version control systems like over a year ago. I used it in my own little projects and everything went smoothly and I really liked it. The idea also caught on at work and my team started a using Git in a fresh project last summer. We did not had so much problems since you can use Git very much like a central vcs like Subversion if you want to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 code metrics you need to watch</title>
      <link>https://example.org/5-code-metrics-you-need-to-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/5-code-metrics-you-need-to-watch/</guid>
      <description>Developing software ain&amp;rsquo;t easy.&#xA;How do you know how you are doing ?&#xA;You could start collecting metrics about your code. These can give you some indication how maintainable and reliable it is.&#xA;The metric which come to mind to the most people is code coverage. Some people say it must be near 100%, other say 80% is a good number. At the end it can&amp;rsquo;t tell you if you are doing great or good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Name your objects right</title>
      <link>https://example.org/name-your-objects-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/name-your-objects-right/</guid>
      <description>Whenever you create an object you have to find a meaningful name.&#xA;While renaming later in modern IDE&amp;rsquo;s is no problem at all you should not pick the first name which comes to your mind.&#xA;Imagine you have an external fraud detection web service and it will return a &amp;lsquo;hit&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;miss&amp;rsquo;. How do you name this object? HitOrMiss maybe (since this is the representation you get from the webservice) ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year of blogging</title>
      <link>https://example.org/one-year-of-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/one-year-of-blogging/</guid>
      <description>One year ago I started to blog again. Time for a little recap. Why did I do it ? I use this blog to write down my own thoughts about software and development. This is for my own reference but also it is a little way to give something back to the world wide community in return for all the useful stuff I do read on the net. I noticed how this also made me a better programmer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s your preferred development infrastructure stack?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/whats-your-preferred-development-infrastructure-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/whats-your-preferred-development-infrastructure-stack/</guid>
      <description>In Response to Matt Raible&#39;s question about my preferred development stack. Source control In my own development project I switched to Git some time ago. I was using svn and before that cvs for a couple of years. Git just makes it easy to try out small ideas very quickly without reverting the code. We will introduce Git at work pretty soon (I hope).&#xA;The Atlassian cloud I was using Confluence as a Wiki in my open source project and my current employer Hypoport uses it as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Selenium2 for web testing (and not Selenium IDE)</title>
      <link>https://example.org/using-selenium2-for-web-testing-and-not-selenium-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/using-selenium2-for-web-testing-and-not-selenium-ide/</guid>
      <description>Selenium IDE Selenium is well know for automatic testing web pages. It does support many browsers, operating systems and languages. A Selenium IDE exists to aid you creating automated tests. It is possible to write extensions in JavaScript to have data driven tests. If you organize your selenium tests in a way that you split the pages and forms in components, you can load up new data for the tests (written in xml) to fill out forms differently for each use case.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Story based daily stand-up meeting</title>
      <link>https://example.org/story-based-daily-stand-up-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/story-based-daily-stand-up-meeting/</guid>
      <description>We are agile. We do Scrum. We do daily Stand-ups.&#xA;A couple of weeks ago we changed our daily stand-up meeting. Our Scrum master came up with the idea to not go around the whole team and everybody talks about what he has done, what he will do and what the impediments are but to make it story based.&#xA;Usually after a break down everybody was working on one story, saw the task cards and made sure he did the things he was supposed to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrate early, integrate often</title>
      <link>https://example.org/integrate-early-integrate-often/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/integrate-early-integrate-often/</guid>
      <description>You are doing scrum, your story is big, you really don&#39;t know much about it and the feature does not get implemented in time.&#xA;Sounds familiar ?&#xA;I had this a couple of times.&#xA;What turned out to be a real problem is that, tech nerds as we are, we spent most of the time coding up a nice solution (and we were almost always convinced that this was the minimum we should have done).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concordion vs. Cucumber and Java based Acceptance Testing</title>
      <link>https://example.org/concordion-vs.-cucumber-and-java-based-acceptance-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/concordion-vs.-cucumber-and-java-based-acceptance-testing/</guid>
      <description>If you want your Business Analyst to provide some acceptance tests for your implementation it would be best to make sure you get it in some form your tests can read. That way you can make sure your code does really do that what the customers wants. Two tools to achieve that are Concordion and Cucumber (and cuke4duke). Both taking the approach of Fit a step further. You can find very good documentation for the tools on their web pages or as examples along with the code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test JBoss Rules 5 (or Drools) with TestNG</title>
      <link>https://example.org/test-jboss-rules-5-or-drools-with-testng/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/test-jboss-rules-5-or-drools-with-testng/</guid>
      <description>We have been using our own flavor of Fit for Rules (which is build on top of fit) for about 1 1/2 years now to test our business logic written in JBoss Rules 5. It&#39;s relatively easy to get the Business Analyst on board since he is using his tool (which is Microsoft Excel) to communicate test cases for the rules. So in theory, he writes the tests in Excel, we do the rules coding and voila, all tests turn green.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How pair programming can help you to get into Test Driven Development</title>
      <link>https://example.org/how-pair-programming-can-help-you-to-get-into-test-driven-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/how-pair-programming-can-help-you-to-get-into-test-driven-development/</guid>
      <description>At my current job management buys into Test driven development. It slowly starts to become our primary development style. Some advantages of TDD for me are: Focus on problem solution No unnecessary development for use cases dreamed up by the developer Always make sure your code fulfills the requirements (tests) If you have tests you can safely refactor your code at any time Even though we all knew about the advantages of TDD, we figured out that we do not always write tests first.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 ways to test your code</title>
      <link>https://example.org/4-ways-to-test-your-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/4-ways-to-test-your-code/</guid>
      <description>Whenever you write some code you better make sure you have it covered by some tests. There are different possibilities on how to achieve this (and you might want to use all of them).&#xA;Unit Tests Unit tests are a classic. You usually write them while you code. Write tests, run failing test, write code and run passing test. Repeat. Keep this small and simple. Test the smallest unit which makes sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get your developers to pay more attention to the burn down chart (and have fun)</title>
      <link>https://example.org/how-to-get-your-developers-to-pay-more-attention-to-the-burn-down-chart-and-have-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/how-to-get-your-developers-to-pay-more-attention-to-the-burn-down-chart-and-have-fun/</guid>
      <description>For the last couple of month our scrum master always drew our daily burn down chart. Nice and fine and it always happened automagically. It came to the point that we (the developers) only occasionally paid attention to it (a little less then we should). One day our scrum master stopped doing it and forced us to do by ourselves. While it seemed a bit strange at first it turns out it was a brilliant idea.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two upgrades to cut down development time</title>
      <link>https://example.org/two-upgrades-to-cut-down-development-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/two-upgrades-to-cut-down-development-time/</guid>
      <description>No matter how good a developer is, with two hardware upgrades you can speed up most machines and cut down development time for everybody.&#xA;Your big fat IDE Depending what you use to crunch out your code, these things are eating your memory. And then you have your application server running, and an internet browser with 20+ sessions, plus Twitter, plus Photoshop, plus, plus, plus.&#xA;I used to have 2 GB RAM in my laptop and I thought it is ok.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with JSF 2 (and Maven)</title>
      <link>https://example.org/getting-started-with-jsf-2-and-maven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/getting-started-with-jsf-2-and-maven/</guid>
      <description>I use Apache Trinidad at work and since JSF 2 is now final I decided to play with it a bit.&#xA;Of course this is going to be the classic Hello World example (as there are many other like this around the web).&#xA;First you need to setup a simple Maven project.&#xA;The file layout should be something like that. After that change your pom.xml to include the servlet and jsf2 libs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update on Quant TestTester</title>
      <link>https://example.org/update-on-quant-testtester/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/update-on-quant-testtester/</guid>
      <description>Here is a small update on my little fun project.&#xA;I released version 0.2 of quant. Now it will recognize all TestNG annotations which do not have a TestNG group (like @BeforeMethod, @BeforeClass etc.). The method &amp;lsquo;reportViolation&amp;rsquo; on ClassTester will now report whats wrong with the examined class.&#xA;assertFalse(classTester.isInvalidTestClass(), classTester.reportViolation()); Above code will now report:&#xA;In this way you know what went wrong and where to look for it. Quant is now also available in my repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quant - Check your Tests</title>
      <link>https://example.org/quant-check-your-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/quant-check-your-tests/</guid>
      <description>Did you ever wondered if all tests your team wrote are really running ? How many disabled tests does your code base have? How many public void methods do not have a @Test annotation (or at the class) ? I saw all of that in the last years.&#xA;To overcome this situation I wrote a couple of java classes which will scan your java test sources and will examine the annotations (for TestNG, sorry JUnit).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jetbrains released a Google App Engine plugin for IntelliJ</title>
      <link>https://example.org/jetbrains-released-a-google-app-engine-plugin-for-intellij/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/jetbrains-released-a-google-app-engine-plugin-for-intellij/</guid>
      <description>Jetbrains released a Google App Engine plugin for their IntelliJ IDE. I did not see any announcement about this at all. You will have a new option when creating a new project. After supplying the path to the local app engine SDK your almost good to go. I needed to add the app engine jars as libraries to my project. That being out of the way you can start coding, run you local server (a pre configured run configuration is supplied) and also deploy it to Google all from within IntelliJ.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ Idea Plugin Property Sorter updated</title>
      <link>https://example.org/intellij-idea-plugin-property-sorter-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/intellij-idea-plugin-property-sorter-updated/</guid>
      <description> I&#39;m pretty busy at work right now but I could find some time to add one more feature to my little property sorter plugin for IntelliJ Idea. Comments above property entries will now be preserved when you sort the file. The plugin is available from within Idea or at Google Code. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to test Spring Webflow 2 (with parent flows)</title>
      <link>https://example.org/how-to-test-spring-webflow-2-with-parent-flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/how-to-test-spring-webflow-2-with-parent-flows/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of month I was writing some flows using Spring Webflow 2. I knew that I (in theory) I could test them but I never did. The overall documentation of Webflow 2 is not that great at the moment, so I hope to improve that a little bit.&#xA;Spring Webflow 2 supports only JUnit tests so far. I guess this will change at some point but until then you have to pull out that junit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Browsers GeoLocation with HTML 5</title>
      <link>https://example.org/getting-the-browsers-geolocation-with-html-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/getting-the-browsers-geolocation-with-html-5/</guid>
      <description>Until now it was almost impossible to get the GeoLocation of a user browsing your site. You could try to use several services to more or less guess the current position. Most of the time they where using the IP address to tackle the problem. This was not very reliable when it came to mobile devices. Ever since the iPhone hit the market mobile adoption of the web grew exponentially.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Look at Google App Engine for Java</title>
      <link>https://example.org/a-quick-look-at-google-app-engine-for-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/a-quick-look-at-google-app-engine-for-java/</guid>
      <description>At Campfire One Google announced their App Engine for Java (this was in the rumor mill for a couple of days already). The first 10,000 developers would get an early look at App Engine&#39;s Java language support. I would have almost missed it. Some tweets reminded me of registering with Google. I heard of AppEngine before but the fact that it was only available for Python did not make it very attractive to me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coloring your IDE</title>
      <link>https://example.org/coloring-your-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/coloring-your-ide/</guid>
      <description>Your IDE does a great job in helping you to program. This includes advanced features like Refactoring, Code completion and support for nifty frameworks. But it can do much more.&#xA;Most of the time you actually read the code instead writing it. So how about to make this a bit more pleasant experience (well it was for me at least). Most of the people I see use the standard color scheme of the IDE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IE7 caches rendered elements?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/ie7-caches-rendered-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/ie7-caches-rendered-elements/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m tasked with some css tweaking to our current product. We need to implement a &amp;lsquo;Print Preview&amp;rsquo; screen so the customer can see how this looks before printing. Css supports exactly this use case with the @media notation.&#xA;So far so good.&#xA;Now Internet Explorer gives me some headache. Basically it looks like that if I render a page and then render the same page again with a slightly different style sheet, the lovely IE (7) will cache the width/text-align of the element.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using TestNG with DataProviders to cover more test cases</title>
      <link>https://example.org/using-testng-with-dataproviders-to-cover-more-test-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/using-testng-with-dataproviders-to-cover-more-test-cases/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago I had the case that I needed to test a method with different parameters. I ended up writing a couple of test methods differing only in passing various arguments to the unit under test.&#xA;Tonight I was at a TestNG talk and while I knew most of the stuff already the DataProviders (which I heard of before but unfortunately never really payed attention to) really caught me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to refactor Spring Webflow variables in your JSF pages with IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://example.org/how-to-refactor-spring-webflow-variables-in-your-jsf-pages-with-intellij-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/how-to-refactor-spring-webflow-variables-in-your-jsf-pages-with-intellij-idea/</guid>
      <description>We are using JSF, Facelets and Spring Webflow in the product I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on. What bugged me for some time already was that when we started to refactor the domain and the corresponding dto&amp;rsquo;s the GUI was a problem since the variables which get pulled out of the webflow are just string declarations. I had to go to each xhtml file and change the code to reflect the access to the new properties.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updated Scrum Board Cheat Sheet with Story Owner</title>
      <link>https://example.org/updated-scrum-board-cheat-sheet-with-story-owner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/updated-scrum-board-cheat-sheet-with-story-owner/</guid>
      <description>So just in the last sprint we (re) discovered that we need an owner of each story. A person who makes sure things are going smoothly and takes care that everything is done in a way so we can fulfill all acceptance tests. At sprint start the person which feels the strongest about the first story will be owner and he will drive the story. Very often we do operate in a king and servant model.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOLID Development Principles In Motivational Pictures (enhanced)</title>
      <link>https://example.org/solid-development-principles-in-motivational-pictures-enhanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/solid-development-principles-in-motivational-pictures-enhanced/</guid>
      <description> I found SOLID Development Principles In Motivational Pictures a couple of days ago. I put one of them up in the restroom. So it turned out some clever colleague enhanced the SRP picture. Nice job. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why our current Sprint commitment will fail</title>
      <link>https://example.org/why-our-current-sprint-commitment-will-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/why-our-current-sprint-commitment-will-fail/</guid>
      <description>We do have our Sprint Review tomorrow. We will not meet our commitment. Bummer.&#xA;What happened?&#xA;After the planning we did the breakdown of almost all stories. We had 5 Stories and another epic. As we did the epic breakdown we knew that we could not nail down every task since it was clear that some refactoring along the user story would be needed. So we marked one card in that story to remind us that we need to break things further down and refine the tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three reasons why you don&#39;t want to use a Spring context in unit tests</title>
      <link>https://example.org/three-reasons-why-you-dont-want-to-use-a-spring-context-in-unit-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/three-reasons-why-you-dont-want-to-use-a-spring-context-in-unit-tests/</guid>
      <description>You use Spring in your application everywhere. You love it. Everything gets injected and is configured by Spring. Great. Why not use the same technology to wire up your tests?&#xA;The bottom line is: Starting the Spring Context all the time in your tests drags you down at the costs of development time.&#xA;Here is why:&#xA;1. Turnaround times are much faster&#xA;When you discover a bug which might have not been covered by tests yet (this happens to me all the time) you are much faster rerunning your tests without the application context.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sorting your properties files in IntelliJ Idea</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sorting-your-properties-files-in-intellij-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sorting-your-properties-files-in-intellij-idea/</guid>
      <description>I do work with language property files pretty much every day (since I&amp;rsquo;m the GUI guy in the team). The files are updated on different branches copied up to the trunk and merged down to new branches, sometimes even updated by our product owner. We got a couple of times into not so funny merge conflicts since people did not sort the property files in the same way. To get around that we used an external tool to sort the files just before committing them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ScrumBoard Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://example.org/the-scrumboard-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/the-scrumboard-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of month we continuously improved our scrum task board. After a sprint planning we usually do a story breakdown into tasks. All tasks for one story get ordered and a time for each will be estimated. We do try do make sure every task is smaller than 8 hours so it can be completed in one day.Our ScrumBoard is a magnetic whiteboard with hand drawn lines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme visibility in an agile environment</title>
      <link>https://example.org/extreme-visibility-in-an-agile-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/extreme-visibility-in-an-agile-environment/</guid>
      <description>What is Extreme visibility?&#xA;Extreme visibility is all about providing information about the code to every team in near real time. We show several metrics such as complexity of the code (xs), todo&amp;rsquo;s, deprecated methods, number of broken builds, open tickets and their priority and so on. These are distributed over a couple of screens which our software is rotating through. Every team member can easily see if his or her commits effecting the code quality in a good or bad way and makes the members aware of certain quality standards we try to keep in our code base.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My MacBook Pro loves 4 GB</title>
      <link>https://example.org/my-macbook-pro-loves-4-gb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/my-macbook-pro-loves-4-gb/</guid>
      <description>I upgraded my MacBook Pro last week to 4 GB of RAM (up from 2GB). It&amp;rsquo;s cheap (about 50 Euros) and it really makes a difference. I can give IntelliJ IDEA 1GB Xmx without any problem. No swapping anymore if I have Idea, Pixelmator, Tomcat, Maven, XMind, Firefox, Mail.app, Tweetdeck and NewsGator running at the same time. Why did I not do it earlier?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA Rulezzz with code completion</title>
      <link>https://example.org/intellij-idea-rulezzz-with-code-completion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/intellij-idea-rulezzz-with-code-completion/</guid>
      <description>Today I got an interesting ctrl+space code completion in IDEA 8.1. Easteregg anyone ? :)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 8.1</title>
      <link>https://example.org/intellij-idea-8.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/intellij-idea-8.1/</guid>
      <description>I do love IntelliJ IDEA but the 8.0 release had some issues with indexing and compiler caches. Version 8.1 is out and addresses these issues (among other things, e.g. git support). Hurray.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behavior driven development with EasyB (and vs. TestNG)</title>
      <link>https://example.org/behavior-driven-development-with-easyb-and-vs.-testng/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/behavior-driven-development-with-easyb-and-vs.-testng/</guid>
      <description>I heard about BDD a couple of months ago and did not really pay attention. Just some weeks ago I thought that maybe I could improve our test and/or documentation. So I decided to give it a shot with the BDD implementation easyb.&#xA;According to Wikipedia:&#xA;So I took the chance to sketch out a little example and to test it against readability.&#xA;This is the class which I would to test with BDD and classic TestNG.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting again</title>
      <link>https://example.org/starting-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/starting-again/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
