<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organization on Oliver Wehrens</title>
    <link>https://owehrens.com/tags/organization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organization on Oliver Wehrens</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://owehrens.com/tags/organization/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Artifacts for effective alignment</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/artifacts-for-effective-alignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/artifacts-for-effective-alignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my professional life, I came across many different companies and organizations. The majority of those were digital companies with its own Tech and Product departments (and only there might the following text applicable). If you have not found your product/market fit, it might be a different game. But if you have, read on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest complications was always the alignment of where to go and how to get there. Does everybody understand the same, is pulling in the same direction, and knows what to do? If you are small enough to fit in a room, things are easier in that regard. The larger you grow and the more remote everybody is, the alignment loses its clear contours. Things will get slower, customer might be unhappy and a clear direction seems to be missing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcast time</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/podcast-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/podcast-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No, I did not start my own. &lt;a href=&#34;https://shows.acast.com/dev-env&#34;&gt;Ivan of dev.env&lt;/a&gt; podcast invited me to talk about how I got there, where I am. Thanks for having me Ivan. It was fun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sorry, German only.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shows.acast.com/dev-env/episodes/18-oliver-wehrens&#34;&gt;https://shows.acast.com/dev-env/episodes/18-oliver-wehrens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How hands-on should a CTO be?</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/how-hands-on-should-a-cto-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/how-hands-on-should-a-cto-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got asked on LinkedIn, so here is my answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It depends (on the phase of the company).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I like Simon Wardley&amp;rsquo;s Mapping. He defines categories of company phases&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pioneers (searching for Product-Market Fit)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Settlers (might have found Product-Market Fit)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Town planners (Found something to grow)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A job in an early startup is very different from a big corporation.  I also assume that while going through the phases, the company grows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sketch Book Summary: No Estimates</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/sketch-book-summary-no-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/sketch-book-summary-no-estimates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is my &lt;a href=&#34;https://owehrens.com/sketch-book-summary-gbs/&#34;&gt;Sketch Book Summary&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://oikosofyseries.com/no-estimates-book-order&#34;&gt;No Estimates&lt;/a&gt; by Vasco Duarte.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;GBS-No-estimates.png&#34; alt=&#34;GBS No Estimates&#34; title=&#34;No Estimates&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four weeks of home office</title>
      <link>https://owehrens.com/four-weeks-of-home-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owehrens.com/four-weeks-of-home-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;homeoffice.png&#34; alt=&#34;Homeoffice&#34; title=&#34;Homeoffice&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On March 12th we decided to send everybody into Home office. We were partially already working remotely but we never tried to be 100%. Now we were forced to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a summary&lt;/strong&gt;: It works better than I expected. The remote work is not as much as a problem for everybody. Being stuck at home is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;tools-dont-fix-problems&#34;&gt;Tools (don’t fix problems)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We already had bits and pieces in place to enable remote collaboration. We already used Slack, Google Hangouts, G-Suite, Asana, Jira, and Confluence. Hangouts is essential for sharing the Desktop or an App for things like core reviews. We added just recently miro.com to the mix as a whiteboard replacement. So far, we are happy with that setup. On the equipment side I am lucky that I have a room in my house as my office. Very quickly after we started working remotely, I ordered a Logitech C920 Webcam. For Audio I use a Jabra Speak 510. Using headphones all the time is possible but with that it is much better. Having a standing desk really helps me to get some movement during the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
